Mary Ann Hoberman Papers 2005.0168
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Mary Ann Hoberman Papers
1961-2010
2005.0168
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
11.1 Linear feet
The collection consists of materials related to children's author Mary Ann Hoberman. The recipient of numerous awards for her children's books and poetry. The materials include her and other authors books, manuscripts, original artwork, poetry, and various administrative records.
Hoberman, Mary Ann
Biography
Mary Ann Hoberman was born on August 12, 1930 in Stamford, Connecticut to Dorothy Miller and Milton Freedman. She attended Stamford public schools, where she wrote for her school newspapers and edited her high school yearbook. In 1951 she received a B.A. in history from Smith College, and later that year married her husband, Norman Hoberman. In 1986 she received an M.A. in English from Yale University.
Hoberman has taught writing and literature from the elementary through the college level. She co-founded and performed with both "The Pocket People," a children's theatre group, and "Women's Voices," a group giving dramatized poetry readings. Although Hoberman did not write her first book until 1957, her interest in writing children's stories began when she was only five years old. And since the publication of her first book, All My Shoes Come in Two's, her primary occupation has been writing children's books. Her books have received a National Book Award, a Society of School Librarians International Best Book award, a National Parenting Publications Award gold medal, and the 2003 Poetry for Children Award of the National Council of Teachers of English. In 2008 she was named the Children's Poet Laureate by the Poetry Foundation.
As a critically acclaimed author of over forty books for children, including A House is a House for Me, Hoberman seeks to help her readers never forget what it felt like to be a child. Hoberman has authored numerous children's books since 1957, and has recently began to branch out and write novels. The Hoberman's have lived in Greenwich, Connecticut for over fifty years in a house designed by Norman Hoberman.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains materials related to children's book author Mary Ann Hoberman. Included in the collection are books, including her own publications, as well as those from other authors. In addition to books the collection is comprised of news clippings, correspondence, manuscripts, financial records, awards, photographs, conference documents, travel itineraries, promotional materials, school correspondence, Books for Young Readers magazines, email correspondence, drawings, artwork, CDs (2) calendars (handmade), drawings from children, thank you letters, writing guides (teachers manual), correspondence with magazines, various poets' work, nature and science, fliers, a National Book Foundation award, poetry by children, children's thank you cards and inspired work, revisions on poetry, Harcourt magazines, and the poem "The Tree that Time Built."
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Provenance and Acquisition
The records were donated to the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center in 2005 by Mary Ann Hoberman.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to children's literature and associated artwork. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Authors, American—20th century—Correspondence.; Children's literature; Children's literature—Manuscripts.; Correspondence.; Manuscripts (document genre).; Manuscripts.; Northeast Children's Literature Collection.; Photographs.
- Series I: Inventory, undated, 1961-2010; Series I:
  - Clippings, publications, correspondence, manuscripts, financial records, awards, 1981-1998 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    [Subjects include: Awards, interviews, children's books, acknowledgements.]
  - Publications, financial records, correspondence, manuscripts, photographs, Bulk, 1993-1998; 1976-1998 (Box 2)
    [Subjects include: Conferences, travel itineraries, promotional materials, school correspondence.]
  - Manuscripts, correspondence, clippings, Bulk, 1989-2010; 1980-2010 (Box 4)
    [Subjects include: Books for Young Readers magazine, thank you responses, email correspondence.]
  - Manuscript, correspondence, drawings, artwork, CDs (2), 1994-1996 (Box 6)
    [Subjects include: Calendar (handmade), drawings from children, thank you letters.]
  - Correspondence, manuscripts, publications, books, 1975-2010 (Box 5)
    [Subjects include: Writing guides (teachers manual), correspondence with magazines.]
  - Publication, manuscript, clippings, correspondence, notes, 2008-2009 (Box 7)
    [Subjects include: Various poets' work, nature and science.]
  - Books, publications, clippings, manuscript, correspondence, fliers, pictures, awards, 1995-1999 (Box 8)
    [Subjects include: National Book Foundation awards, thank you letters, poetry by children.]
  - Clippings, photograph, artwork (minor wear/tear on some of the work), fliers, manuscripts, publications, 1993-1996 (Box 9)
    [Subjects include: Children's thank you cards and inspired work, revisions on poetry.]
  - Correspondence, book, publication, 1974-2009 (Box 10)
    [Subjects include: Children's literature.]
  - Books, publications, 1973-2005 (Box 11)
    [Subjects include: Children's books by various authors, Harcourt magazine.]
  - Publications, 1974-2002 (Box 12)
    [Subjects include: Magazines for children.]
  - Artwork, publication, notes, undated (Box 13)
    [Subjects include: Poem "The Tree that Time Built," children's artwork/poems.]
  - Notes, Correspondence, Artwork, Photographs, Publications, Books, 1961-2006 (Box 14)
    [Subjects include: Thank you letters/artwork, biography of Mary Ann Hoberman, catalogues.]